[Music]
so throughout your journey can you tell
us about any one contribution that
you've made to ogilvy there will
definitely be many but like the one that
you spoke about the ad uh you know
probably no matter how big or small it
is but it is really close to your heart
yeah sure you know and and i'm not going
to talk about advertising because like
if you ask me for one contribution that
i've made to ogilvy that i will remember
and cherish for the rest of my life
across these 16 years
um it is not a piece of advertising it's
not a campaign
um it's culture
right
but what i think the impact that i've
made the most
um is on making people feel happier in
the company they are
making people happier about where they
work who they work with how they work
um
you know i think that that to my mind is
the single most important job i could
have done
um
either as the ceo or as a business head
with my team or as a as a business unit
head handling you know the digital side
of the business
everywhere i've gone
um i've tried to make people happier in
the work that they do
and that results in better work
but it more importantly results in
happier people in the country
um that's to my to me that's the most
important thing there's one thing i will
remember it's that
amazing sir so sir like you're talking
about uh in the culture so so we both
were very curious to know what a day in
the life of a ceo of an advertising
agency looks like
um when when you're an account executive
uh or let me let me make this in the
first person when i was an account
executive
um i was deeply involved in
every single thing that went out on a
brand right
because it was my job to make sure it
went out on time to check it to make
sure it was error free so i was deeply
involved right i would read every word
of the copy make sure there was there
were no double spaces no no typos no
spelling errors um you know make sure
the material was fine make sure it was
delivered on time make sure you know my
my
my project excel sheets were running on
schedule uh wherever there were gaps i
was just pushing people to get stuff
done so it's very operational but it's
very operational and linked to the brand
and to deliverables on the brand
um
you know i fast forward a few years
later when i became an account director
um which is a designation you get to six
seven years down the line in the
advancing business
um
the bulk of my job was was supervising
stuff right and starting to build client
relationships
um so you know i was spending more time
talking to clients understanding what
they need spending a lot of time in
market talking to consumers trying to
get into the heart of the brand
contributing a little strategy
leaving the operational side to the
current executives but still knowing
what's happening being able to control
it and supervise it right
um
when i grew from there to let's say
client servicing director managing
supervisor vice president because all
those designations mean the same thing
right
um
my focus there was on on strategy
and on client relationships
on making sure the client felt they had
somebody they could trust
somebody who was leading their business
somebody who knew
where they wanted to take the brand
in the year in the next two years in the
next three years
and that requires a bigger picture it
requires it required me to have a point
of view on
what consumers felt where they were
likely to move how the brand was
positioned where we wanted to move the
brand
what the work should look like what the
brand world should look like what the
consumer experience of the brand should
be like right
um i still needed to make sure my
account directors and my eas were on
track projects moving on schedule but
that was more of a supervisory role the
bulk of it was the relationship with
client making sure they had the best of
the company right
the best resources the best people the
best thinking
um making sure they had they felt like
they had a strong partner
um and and really building that
relationship in the brand over time
and influencing the work right at that
stage when you're in in the cst
management supervisor vp even the
account director role they're also
focused on improving the quality of the
work you want the work to be better and
better and better so you're deeply
involved in every in every script
presentation in the ppms in the shoots
right in the client presentations making
sure everything is perfect right
the orchestration works like like a like
you know like like a great team
performing well
when you get to an office head role
which is something i did for a while or
a business head role where you're
heading like i'm selling the digital
team which is 150 people
uh servicing a bunch of clients across
the country um at that time you start
focusing on um the p l right saying are
we profitable are we making enough are
we growing fast enough first of all
because you know growth drives
everything if you have enough revenue
growth you're happy down the line you're
able to you know your margins improve
you're able to support your people with
increments all of that growth is the
engine that drives all of us so the
focus is on new business it's on
pitching getting new clients in
identifying the clients you want to work
with
um and making that uh you know something
that you do intentionally saying which
are the 10 clients i want to work with
how do i bring those 10 clients into the
company how do i make sure each client
is operating profitably and how do i
make sure we're growing
hiring the best people at that level
your focus is on talent spotting and
bringing them in and keeping them in the
company uh then putting the best people
on the best businesses finding the right
match
um you have a you know extremely
talented person but you want you know
you want to make sure he or she is
aligned to the business that will best
leverage the talent he or she has
and it's a lot of that
uh and you're still involved in key
client relationships because they keep
coming to you when there's an escalation
mainly right when you're an office head
or a business that's saying hey i'm
struggling this team is not working or
this brand is not working
this production house is an issue or
something is delayed and you manage
those escalations as well right
um
when you get to the ceo position
you are most far removed from the work
um and that's something everybody needs
to understand and come to terms with
right when you get to this position you
have to trust other people to do the
work
i have to trust my office heads the vice
presidents the senior vice presidents
the ecb's gcds ccos to do fabulous work
right
um
if i start interfering in everybody's
work and saying here i have a point of
view on this film and that script and
this client
um i'm not letting them do their jobs
right i need to let them grow into their
jobs
um so the question is what do you do as
a ceo then and here's the answer right
um in in any average week um the bulk of
my time
goes in in human resource issues
um
which is things people are struggling
with in the company
uh and and trying to iron out
pathways clear pathways break down
barriers
um manage conflict
within the company and with clients
right so the kind of escalation that
comes to you and the ceo when you're the
ceo is when the really hits the fan
right so it's the most complex client
escalations the most complex people
escalations
um so you're not looking at the work but
you're you're talking to a client who is
extremely upset about something right
either their work hasn't been delivered
or their people have quit or um you know
their business is tanking or
um you know there's something happening
in your agency which they're extremely
unhappy about
and it's about solving those those the
has already hit the fan you know
step in and solve it something anybody
else couldn't solve right you need to
step in and solve those
so it is the it is the the dirtiest the
most complex issues that you will get
dragged into from a client perspective
the dirtiest the most complex issues you
will get dragged into from people and
talent perspective right
that's the day-to-day job
um then there are finance issues right
which is you know we need to hire 20
people
the region is not approving the highers
worldwide is not approving the highers
because there's some issues with your
financial numbers cleaning that up
fighting the system to get what you need
um and it's a lot of it's a lot of fire
fighting on a day-to-day basis
but what the job is really about and
that you know it's not about an average
day but
but what you make time for in the year
um what the job is about is about
charting a path for the organization
not for a company not for a brand as not
for a client brand not for the clients
company but for your own company it's
you as the brand right
how do i take ogilvy and char the path
for obd and what's the brand point of
view for ob how do we want clients to
see it in market what are the
initiatives we need to take so clients
actually see us that way right
um
and it's not just imagery but it's
actual
vision and operations as well right
which are the companies we want to
acquire why do we want to acquire them
when we apply them how do we assimilate
them into the company
what are the new services we need to
launch how will we launch those services
how would it work financially what's the
return for those services in a six month
field in a one year period and 18 months
right what's the business case you can
make for them who are the key people to
put in the best roles right that's it's
a critical part of the job
you have a bunch of leaders i you know
i'd say today i have 20 25 leaders
across the company who are
all ready to take senior management role
or in senior management roles of
different kinds right what do i do with
their careers where do they move next
who's best position to lead something in
an office or to lead a specific business
or a capability um you know or who's
who's best position to launch something
new mentor it and take it through right
who's best position to take an
acquisition
and and help it integrate into the
company uh it's those questions it's
moving those pieces around while you're
managing all the in the escalations
right
and and really trying to get to a point
where at the end of the year you look
back and say the company is moved it's
moved forward in a certain direction and
that direction is the direction which
you wanted to take it
that's that's the job